Wil Buchanan

williamjamesbuchanan@gmail.com | 863-259-0202 | linkedin.com/in/williamjamesbuchanan | wijabu.github.io

EXECUTIVE SUMMARY

An aspiring full-stack web developer with six years of technical solutions experience in the hospitality industry. A creative problem solver pivoting careers and bringing diverse experience from both military and civilian positions who thrives on communication and curiosity.

EXPERIENCE

Director, Data Integrity Experience Operations – LMS, Inc.

July 2021 – Feb 2023

- Directed team of Data Analysts to evaluate and resolve issue trends disrupting guest and crew experiences
- Lead Data Integrity Pod through Agile development of PII security and consistency throughout ecosystem
- Scripted JavaScript toolset to automate fixes to common issues; reduced incident resolution time by 75%

Public Affairs Superintendent – Florida Air National Guard

Sep 2018 – May 2023

- Supervised, trained and certified Multimedia Journalists in Associated Press, journalism and photography
- Built cloud-based dynamic schedule to organize strategies and trends, reducing man hours by 60%
- Managed 48 Airmen across 14 counties to distribute 87,083 COVID-19 vax for Operation Warp Speed

Project Manager & Application Support Lead – LMS, Inc.

Sep 2019 - July 2021

- Designed holistic Jira roadmap tracking multiple projects to report real-time status updates to VPs
- Investigated Major Incidents and trends to pinpoint root causes to Problems and code permanent solutions
- Compiled APIs to recreate Guest Experience; tested via JavaScript; uncovered gaps among microservices

Senior Technical Integration Specialist & Business Analyst – LMS, Inc.

Mar 2017 – Sep 2019

- Tested the Guest Experience in a live production environment; recorded new friction points and use cases
- Produced text and video training materials; trained fellows on rapid resolution of common guest problems
- Tracked, managed, and solved incidents via ServiceNow; integrated with PagerDuty to automate alerting

EDUCATION

| Web Development Bootcamp – Full-stack web applications – Udemy | 2023 |
|--|------|
| Master of Arts - Cognitive Science & Interpersonal Communication - University of Central Florida | 2013 |
| Bachelor of Arts – Journalism – University of Central Florida | 2009 |

LANGUAGES, SKILLS AND TOOLS

| | JavaScript | Express | ServiceNow |
|---|------------|--------------------------------|---------------------------------------|
| | HTML | ■ SQL | Jira / Confluence |
| | CSS | MongoDB | ■ Agile |
| - | NodeJS | Git / GitHub | |